Igor Popov

iOS enthusiast with over 14 years of experience in native iOS development. I excel at developing apps from the ground up and leading the development process. Driven by creating apps that are both useful and enjoyable for users, while continuously improving team performance and productivity.

popov.kakdela@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/oboje https://ipopov.dev location: Europe

- Proficiency in Swift and in-depth knowledge of the iOS SDK
- Comprehensive understanding of various architectural approaches, with a focus on reliability, testability, and A/B testing
- Solid understanding of multithreading behavior
- Successful track record of taking technical ownership of an iOS app serving millions of users
- Expertise in implementing automation and establishing efficient processes, bringing a new level of velocity and transparency to development
- Skilled at building and leading high-performing teams

EXPERIENCE

Super Unlimited — Senior iOS Engineer

October 2021 - present (remote)

Developing the #1 VPN on the App Store, with 5M+ MAU. Driving app technical design and new feature development in collaboration with stakeholders.

- Refactored and restructured a legacy Objective-C app using Swift, MVVM + Combine + SwiftUI, and SPM, resulting in a modern, modular, and organized codebase that enabled team scaling and increased the flow of new features.
- Developed a framework for managing promo campaigns with remote paywall customization, streamlining A/B testing, reducing time to market, and boosting trial conversion to paid users, which led to increased revenue
- Implemented a major app update with SwiftUI, introducing single sign-on across the platforms with a unified account system
- Achieved a more than 30% increase in ad revenue through full ads refactoring, which
 involved new strategies, optimized ad provider calls, and adopting new ad caching
 techniques
- Improved the VPN connection's ability to handle faults and resist blocking by implementing a new client service for discovering and resolving VPN configurations
- Introduced and configured CI/CD processes to automate product delivery and resource dependency stack assembly
- Automated several manual processes, reducing a full day of developer work to a 5-minute automated job.

Aura (ex Anchorfree/Pango) — Senior iOS Engineer

2019 - 2021(remote)

Developed top 5 VPN on the App Store, a white label VPN product:

- Refactored several VPN applications into monorepo, by breaking feature and functionality into smaller, isolated components(frameworks) using VIPER.
- Made changes to the legacy user tracking systems through coding and refactoring, leading to a 90% improvement in data cleanliness as a result of unification and implementation.
- I optimized three phases of manual work across three departments, which involved managing and distributing client data analytics requirements. This process reduced the deployment costs of new requirements from ~4 weeks to ~3 days.

SKILLS

iOS native development

Swift, Objective-C

Unit testing, Integration Testing, UI Tests

Architecture/solution design

SOLID, concurrent programming, reactive programming

MVC/MVVM/VIPER

TOOLS / FRAMEWORKS

Combine, RxSwift, SwiftUI, UIKit, Lottie, Snapkit

StoreKit, Firebase, Adapty/RevenueCat, FirebaseDistribution, Crashlytics

fastlane, Xcode Cloud

openapi, sourcery, xcodegen, quicktype, swiftgen

LANGUAGES

LEAPFROG GROUP — Senior iOS Engineer

2018 - 2019

Worked as a key developer for a video chat app for disabled people. Performed fixes for critical bugs and implemented new features for the app.

- Improved product crash-free rate to 99.9%
- Modularized application
- Refactored code to be testable, covered 30% of the code with tests.

Freelancing, Ukraine — iOS Engineer

2017 - 2018

Accomplished several iOS projects as a freelancer.

- Developed social network SDK using Swift & VIPER for Microsoft from scratch
 - Developed a multi-component social network feed page including pagination, UI/UX & networking
- Developed baby monitor app with native audio and video streaming from scratch
 - Custom components with custom animations #CoreAnimation
 - H264 encoding/decoding video pipelines, Opus for audio streaming
 - Networking layer for RPC, media streaming & session control signaling
 - o Client/Server modes for application.

DataArt, Ukraine — iOS Engineer

2013 - 2016

Worked as iOS Software Engineer in an outsourcing IT company, mostly worked for US customers, and took part in different activities: pre-sales, team leading, developing projects from scratch, and project support.

GlobalLogic, Ukraine — iOS Engineer

2012 - 2013

Was part of prototypes & experiments team, developed several iOS applications from scratch for the healthcare domain.

Gameloft, Ukraine — iOS Engineer / iOS Game Developer

2010 - 2012

Developed real-time, multiplayer games for iOS platform using C++ and Objective-C

EDUCATION

National Aerospace University, Kharkiv, Ukraine — *Software Engineering, Bachelor*

2007 - 2011

I have a background in <u>software engineering</u>, and while studying this field, I created a few e-commerce projects using PHP. Later on, I became interested in C++ and OpenGL, which led me to pursue game development on the iOS platform.

NOTICEABLE PROJECTS

VPN app 2021-present

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/vpn-super-unlimited-proxy/id1370293473

VPN app 2019 - 2021

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hotspotshield-vpn-wifi-proxy/id443369807 https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ultra-vpn-unlimited-vpn-proxy/id1053874290 https://apps.apple.com/us/app/best-vpn-proxy-betternet/id946659216 Social App Swift Framework for Microsoft 2018 https://github.com/Microsoft/EmbeddedSocial-iOS-SDK Multiplayer Game 2012 https://www.gameloft.com/en/game/six-guns/